history will know that in
1969 we went to the moon and then since
then we have not seen an American world
record the way that we just did with
Hampton Morris that's the scope of what
we're looking at here I hope more folks
follow in Patty's footsteps and I hope
that her stepping on the platform and
putting herself out there I hope this
inspires more people to compete
honorable exit tantau has a resume for
the record books uh but it a really
tough way to to to end off against
leean hello and welcome to strength
weekly I'm recording from a hotel room
which means you know I'm on the run but
someone who's not on the run is Phil
bman Phil we have a great show today
which of these stories are you most
excited about don't say the title give
me a number one through four oh one it's
got to be one going with the kickoff the
kickoff of the show kickoff show well
let's get into the Run of show Hampton
Morris weightlifter for the United
States 61 kg sets the first American
Senior World Records in over 50 years
takes silver at the iwf World Cup and
comes away with a world record TI heart
attack to and an Olympic silver medalist
retires from the sport of weightlifting
at the international level Olivia Reeves
of the United States punch her tickets
to Paris and cements herself as a gold
medal Contender to round out the day one
of the biggest Fitness influencers in
the world you might know her from social
media you might know her from YouTube
Lean be Patty steps on the power lifting
platform for the first time and wins her
weight category we talked about
influencers and competition and the
crossover in the fitness and strength
World Phil let's get to the iwf World
Cup it was the last chance qualifier for
folks who want to compete in
weightlifting at the Paris
Olympics for context there aren't a lot
of spots in weightlifting at the Paris
Olympics there aren't that many weight
classes and teams can send a maximum I a
maximum of Three Men and three women to
Paris one of these smaller Olympic
weightlifting competitions that we've
seen in the last 20 odd years but one
weightlifter who punched his ticket to
Paris young Hampton Morris of the United
States 61 kilogram male who has a Litany
of Junior records set the first senior
men's world record for the United States
since the
1960s what happened what did Morris do
and wait a minute why did he still come
in second place yeah so the way that it
ends up working out is uh history will
know that in
1969 we went to the moon and then since
then we have not seen an American world
record the way that we just did with
Hampton Morris that's the scope of what
we're looking at here so Hampton Morris
he scored 124 kg snatch a 176 kg
cleaning jerk that's your alltime world
record Junior world record the whole
shebang and then he scored a 303
kilogram total now he didn't score the
gold the gold went to China we went to
leaan he scored 312 kilograms so he beat
Morris by nine kilograms overall in the
day but it let's caveat here real quick
because even though Hampton set this
like alltime world record that we
haven't seen in well before we were born
I know that we're old David but well
before we were born that is an
accomplishment that we cannot understate
by comparison even though he did not
stand on top of the podium at the end of
the day like this is a Historic Landmark
I'm so excited that Hampton's going to
be competing in Paris this was
phenomenal all right let's just give
give folks a rundown Hampton moris
snatched 124 kilos then clean and jerked
176 kilos as a 61 kilo male total 303
kilograms he finished in second place
overall by the way that cleaning jerk
that 176 kilo cleaning jerk a world
record that was the biggest cleaning
jerk of the session the biggest cleaning
jerk this bodyweight category has ever
seen since the body weight category
restructuring 176 kilos since a 61
kilogram male teetering up approaching
hinting at a three times body weight
cleaning jerk but only finished in
second place overall because leab of
China extended his own world record in
the snatch with 146 kilos so even though
Morris out clean and jerked Lee Lee out
snatch Morris by more than 20 kilograms
and therefore comfortably
took the gold medal Lee is in a C is in
a class of his own when it comes to the
snatch in this category normally the
Klean and jerk seals the deal but for
Lee he's snatching so much more than
Morris that he is the favorite he won
the gold medal by a healthy margin and
he is clearly the favorite heading into
Paris right Morris safe to say he is a
metal
Contender but he would have to do
something remarkable and Lea faab would
have to have a terrible day for Le being
to not win golden Paris that being said
Morris clean and jerking 176 kgs the
first American to hold a world record at
the senior level now some Americans have
held world records including Hampton at
the youth and Junior levels first
American to hold a world record at the
senior level since Bob bednarski in
1969 we're talking moon landing years so
congrats to Hampton Morris still young
so accomplished a metal Contender
heading into Paris a world record you
love to see it you love to see it Phil
do you do you think that going into
Paris that it seems like a gold medal is
Out Of Reach just because Lee is so far
ahead but do you think Morris when we
say metal Contender are we are we
thinking that like silver is in his
future is like is is he going to be is
he going to be clean and jerking knowing
that a silver medal is on the line is
that is that the future that it holds
for America my prediction is that at the
Paris Olympics in the men's 61 kilogram
session Hampton Morris is going to have
at least one clean one clean JK attempt
perhaps
two where a silver medal is on the
line that is my prediction now fabine
could Lea fabine could have a bad day
Lee fabine could have a bad day but Lee
fabine is so exemplary in the snatch the
world record holder in the snatch and so
far ahead of his competition that I
really do think unless he has a terrible
day the race is going to be for silver
and bronze and I do believe my
prediction is that Hampton Morris is
going to have at least one clean and
attempt perhaps
two wherein a silver medal is on the
line that's my prediction folks that's
my prediction I do want to give a shout
out to Hampton Morris someone who's been
making steady progress for us
weightlifting has had the best quad the
Olympic qualification cycle the best
fouryear quad foure quad redundant best
four years the best quad of any American
male any American male I would say
Hampton Morris has been exemplary very
excited comp beete in Paris still a very
young lifter he's been on the barbed
podcast um his rise is a in his teens to
one of the top men's competitors at the
senior level in the world is great he
doesn't show any signs of slowing down
it seems like every other time he takes
the platform in competition he's setting
some sort of PR or world
record I'm excited to see if he stays in
the 61 kilogram bodyweight category can
he make a run at the triple body weight
clean and jerk a very rare feet in
weightlifting one of the rarest Feats in
weightlifting we'll see we'll see but
sure as heck fun to
watch yeah it is let's go up in wait and
let's talk
about another Chinese weightlifter not
leab beIN one of his teammates
tnau tnw after the iwf World Cup he will
not be competing in Paris he did not
qualify tienta announces his retirement
from the sport of weightlifting at the
international level now he will still be
competing domestically in China which is
pretty intense competition I should say
but
tiau retiring from the sport of
weightlifting let's talk a little bit
about tient when you hear the name
tient Phil besides a name that sounds
like my own even though we are actually
not related we joke about that but tant
and I are not related what do you think
of when you think of tantow so after
covering tent for I don't know how many
years at this point but the one thing
that always comes to mind is when we
would cover his training lifts he always
has the most insane back squats like the
dude like I feel like you can put any
amount of weight on his back and he will
be able to squat it all the way like
deep in dep like deep depth Squat and
it's just remarkable like how much
muscle is just packed onto his back
whenever we watch him squat so like the
thing that stands out to me is his
specifically his training in the back
squat while he's in any of his
preps okay let's talk about tant's day
at the iwf World Cup he had an outside
chance of qualifying he basically had to
beat his teammate in the same body
weight category men's 89 Lee
Lee D shows no shine signs of showing
down right ta snatched 171 kilos missed
his next two attempts at 176 177 did not
record a successful clean and jerk he
basically had to exceed a 396 kilo total
which was Hefty and again he was an
outside Prospect of this quad because
Lee D's progress has been remarkable
China cannot send was not gonna send
both of them to the Olympics could not
send both of them to the Olympics tnau
Olympic silver medalist from the Rio
Olympics had the nickname heart attack
because of and I
quote from Barbed Zone Jake Dixon
adoringly nicknamed heart attack for his
coin flip success rate on the lifting
platform taao has filled his metal
cabinet with plenty of hardware and
offed by the skin of his teeth 18
International competition appearances in
11 years won the Asian games of 2014 at
age 28 International Event wins overall
Olympic silver medalist in Rio 2019
world champion in Ty land 181 kilo
snatch lifetime competition record at a
96 kilo body weight just to be clear and
a clean and jerk world record holder in
the 96 kilo body weight at 231 kilograms
just worth noting he was competing at 89
kilograms here tantau incredibly strong
fun competitor but every time he took
the platform you were like on the edge
of your seat because you didn't know if
you're going to see a like his success
rate especially in kleaning jerks not
super high but good enough to come away
with some Hardware over an 11-year
International career that's for sure
yeah and he came into this event as you
said outside chance but also I mean
trying to outdo Lee Diane is an
impossible task in the current day that
we live in like that is just put put
anybody up against them there're it it
is going to be an impossible task
regardless so honorable exit tantau has
a resume for the record books uh but it
a really tough way to to to send off
against Lee Dian tnw We Salute You
here's one for the road Thanks for the
Memories thanks for the adrenaline
rushes the UPS the downs tnau one of the
most exciting weight lters to watch
certainly over the last decade wishing
you a happy retirement from
International competition though it
seems like we will be seeing him back in
national competition in China all right
let's move on to the women's 71 kg
category a weight lifter who has a lot
more makes than misses on the
international platform over the last
couple years Olivia not heart attack
Olivia ice in her veins
Reeves how did Reeves do on the day at
her iwf World Cup session so she had an
excellent day she actually pushed her
own Junior World Records uh she beat
both uh China and North Korea in the
process of putting up the following
numbers in this snatch she successfully
hit 112 115 118 kg in the cleaning jerk
142 147 150 kilg that gave her a total
of 268 kg what a day Olivia Reeves locks
up her spot in Paris we kind of knew
that we kind of knew coming in she was
going to represent Paris now this is a
tough category coming into the quad
there was some immense Talent Alivia
Reeves young lifter still a she she by
the way is 20 years old so kind of could
be a junior but she turns 21 this year
so by iwf International standards is
actually not a junior weight liting is
all about the year you're born not
exactly how old you are so coming into
this quad the three women's names in
these in this like 10 kilo body weight
range were Kate vibert who was a silver
medalist from the Tokyo Olympics
Meredith allwine world champion at the
senior level Maddie
Rogers Olympian from
Tokyo also a multi-time medalist at the
world senior level Olivia Reeves is the
one heading to Paris phenomenal progress
over the last few years from Reeves
really pushed
numbers just like way ahead I mean she
is like she is just owning these
American records in a big way at the
bodyweight category snatching 118 clean
jerking 150 I mean she holds these
American it's just extending her
American records bit by bit she won by a
pretty big margin with her 268 kilo
total and you could argue and we did in
an article covering this performance
that this is the first time an American
woman has ever beat athletes from both
China and North Korea in the same
session by a significant ific margin so
Reeves not only puts herself into the
conversation as a metal contender in
Paris she
is potentially a metal favorite heading
into Paris now she's sitting in second
place overall in the rankings so it's a
little tough to say but still lifter
who's making a lot of progress from one
competition to the next Phil it's not
ridiculous to think that if Olivia
Reeves has herself a day in Paris she
could come away with a gold medal do you
think the adrenaline of her first
Olympic Games is something that she'll
be able to manage on the platform we've
seen her be very consistent and progress
over time on the world stage before but
is the is the Olympic Games different
the Olympic Games is always different
right of course the Olympic Games is
different but I'm gonna be honest with
you I have never competed at the Olympic
Games so I don't really know breaking
news breaking news DAV breaking news
breaking news sorry I haven't yet
competed at the Olympic Games and
weightlifting news broken news let's
broken news let's do it that way but
Olivia Reeves is someone who performs
well on stage she shows up and she has
had a string of successful competition
after successful competition she doesn't
always go six for six but she's had a
lot of five for six and six for six
performances incredibly consistent I
think I'm gonna go with ice in her veins
I think Olivia Olivia ice in her veins
Reeves I'm going to throw it out there
my prediction is uh for American medals
I think Hampton Morris silver I think
Olivia Reeves gold th those are my
predictions for American medals but then
again that's not even to talk about I
mean we know we know the other two women
going to Paris to represent the United
States in weightlifting Mary Tyson Lin
at super heavy and Jordan Del La Cruz at
49 kilos I'm stoked I'm excited and
we'll be tuning in and bringing you all
the action leading up to the Paris
Olympics
including metal
predictions it's a lot of weightlifting
on the let's move over to the sport of
powerlifting lean beef patty one of the
biggest Fitness influencers in the world
competed in powerlifting for the first
time the name on the scorecard she
competed as Patricia Patty not lean beef
patty officially on the scorecard her
first ever powerlifting competition or
competitive powerlifting outing it's
always interesting because we've seen a
lot of competitive strength athletes
move over to the influencer side or
build significant followings on YouTube
and other platforms based on their
success on the platform lean be Patty
going the other way around Phil
competing at 60 kilos how did Patty do
so Patty competed as you said at 60
kilograms at the 2024 USPA 2 infinite
and Beyond in Coast Mesa California the
27-year-old she went eight for n in
attempts not too shabby on her first
outing here were her here was her
performance she scored 1272 kilos on the
squat 80 kilos on the bench press and
1422 kilos on the deadlift for a 342
half kilogram total now she competed
uncontested in the 60 kgam division she
did have to post a total though in order
to technically win her division so even
though she didn't have competition which
to be fair if you're going into your
first powerlifting meet pretty nice to
not have to worry about like you know
the the people around you engaging in
that way but she did uh relay to her
extremely large fan base the particulars
of competing in your first powerlifting
meet that aren't as obvious to some some
who's just thinking I just need to hit
the biggest lifts in particular she
relayed a couple of instances where she
learned how to Tempo with the judge's
commands to lift properly that way a
lift wouldn't be flagged as a no lift
for missing the judge's command or what
have you so the timing of when you lift
when you ascend all of those things
whether it's on the bench or the squat
she like was navigating that in real
time and that was fun to watch from
somebody who is competing uncontested so
she doesn't necessarily have other
people that she can watch in her do the
same thing and she was relaying that to
her to her F but yes when you compete in
a sanction meet you have to listen for
your judge to give you the down command
before you can lift and then you have to
hold the lift until they tell you to
Rack it so pretty good performance 342
and a half kilos I I think more
impactful than the total here is that
it's it's one of the most popular
fitness influencers in the world getting
on the platform and setting an example
like Patty never had to ever compete
never had to step on the platform never
never had to max out her lifts you know
in public view honestly she does very
well as a fitness influencer there was
no external pressure really for her to
do this she's got a great career as an
influencer I I hope she makes a lovely
living from that from sponsorships
advertising dollars
Etc but I gotta say I love seeing I love
seeing people who are influencers moving
over and actually competing and actually
attempting competitive Athletics
especially in the fitness realm now I'm
not going to get into the whole Jake
Paul versus Mike Tyson thing right now
as far as influencers changing over to
athletes or getting to that realm but I
hope more folks follow imp Patty's
footsteps and I hope that her stepping
on the platform and putting herself out
there I hope this inspires more people
to compete I think back to the example
uh Meg Gallagher AKA Meg squats was a
competitive lifter competitive
powerlifter and built her social media
following and YouTube following
basically
as she was competing and after her
competition days were basically behind
her after she stopped competing
regularly she might do it again in the
future Patty's going the other direction
here Larry Wheels someone who was one of
the best powerlifters in the world and
then started from that to really build
an Engaged following Brian Shaw building
a massive YouTube fan base social media
fan base after being one of the world's
top strong men it's really cool to see
influencers going the other way because
I think that actually inspires people in
a very different way and and really
reminds folks that yeah you can get in
the gym you can enjoy training but these
are also Real Sports you can really
compete and there's great Community
behind that that's what I liked about
Patty's video especially in her video
coverage and recap was it highlighted
the community aspect the learning aspect
and honestly it got me wanting to step
on the platform I was like this looks
like a great experience this is a great
atmosphere she learned some really cool
things I think folks like Patty doing
this and putting themselves out there
encourages people to get involved in the
competition side and power lifting which
is what we want because strength sports
are for everyone they're amazing
experiences you know like I've competed
I've competed in strength Sports I
remember my first time stepping on the
weightlifting platform I didn't lift
much weight at all I was one of the
worst people there I was one of the
weakest lifters there but I had such an
amazing time and I made friends through
that process that I still have to this
day and it really helped my
self-confidence it helped myself self
perception I just can't speak highly
enough to the influencers that don't
have to but choose to compete even if
they're not really competing against
anyone showing up to a competition doing
this in public kudos to you lean beef
patty because I think it's that it's
these people with a lot of eyeballs
choosing to do this that will have an
outsize impact on growing the sports the
strength Sports and legitimizing
strength Sports as great positive
outlets for physical culture and
expression and
rant I think that was an Exquisite rant
uh to to close the show on but I do want
to also tag on to the end of that that
for anybody who is considering competing
listen to lean batty when she says that
when she competes on the day it actually
wasn't as strenuous as she thought
because you only have to go up and do
singles at a time so if you're used to
huffing and puffing in the gym in your
training the competition platform might
be a a nice way to test your max lifts
but you're not going to be like sweating
sweating your your hair out all right so
I give it a I will disagree with that
Phil I will say power lifting
competitions if you are as you gain
experience and as you are able to
understand like push yourself and push
yourself you know in that 100 plus
percentage range I actually would argue
that between warm-ups and nine platform
attempts a powerl competition is
actually quite exhausting now when
you're just starting out and you might
not be as experienced an athlete on the
platform and you don't know really how
to push yourself maybe you're not pring
maybe you're not going above your gym
PRS it it might not be you know it might
not be the hardest session you've ever
had but I would argue I will disagree
with you a little Phil and say that as
you progress in the sport and as you
learn to give it more of your all and as
you learn to really tap into um how to
get the most out of your performance on
the platform and you are eing out every
kilo and fighting for every kilo I would
actually argue nine near Max or above
Max attempts on the day on the Power
Platform are pretty darn exhausting
because you also have to count the
warm-ups to get to those it's not like
you're just doing nine lifts right
you're doing percentage work to warm up
to that so Phil I love you
respectfully respectfully
disagree maybe more in the realm of
folks who have competition experience
under their belt if you're a beginner
you might not even know your Maxes right
so it's a little bit more guesswork and
you're kind of basing off feel it can be
a fun day you can kind of treat it like
a training session but
again one of the few instances where
Phil and lechman and I will
disagree Phil you do that to rile me up
didn't you I mean David when you said
you wanted to get back on the lifting
platform you need you need a cheering
fan base to to get you riled up to hit
those numbers
who who better who better than me I'll
tell you what my therapist had said the
only fan that really matters is you wow
wow big if true big if true well we're
fans of all the lifters we covered today
make sure to join us on strength lle
next week because we'll have even more
updates including some alltime powering
world records that we did not have time
to fit into this broadcast Phil thanks
so much for joining me it is always an
immense and extreme
pleasure